<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Post on My blog</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/</link><description>Recent content in Post on My blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 21:05:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Covid Vaccine 2 Temperatures</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-05-07-covid-vaccine-2-temps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 21:05:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-05-07-covid-vaccine-2-temps/</guid><description>Some temperature data</description></item><item><title>some ffmpeg stitching</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-05-23-ffmpeg-stitching/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-05-23-ffmpeg-stitching/</guid><description>using ffmpeg to stitch together some images into a slide show</description></item><item><title>Notes on hugo</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-05-16-hugo-notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-05-16-hugo-notes/</guid><description>Switched from Jekyll to Hugo</description></item><item><title>Noom Gdpr</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-05-02-noom-gdpr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 13:08:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-05-02-noom-gdpr/</guid><description>How to download your Noom data Per this note, you can apparently download your Noom data here
I used this because I completely forgot what a serving was for one of my custom recipes On Noom all I can see is that my &amp;ldquo;KetoGranola20210326&amp;rdquo; , 1 serving is 187 Cal. But if I have a trusty food scale and I want to log 149g I need to know what that is for a serving.</description></item><item><title>Some Better Desk Research</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-04-10-standing-desk-hmm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-04-10-standing-desk-hmm/</guid><description>2021-04-10 Tust trawling image search for some inspiration Clamped From here, like the clamp since it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take over your entire desk. But I&amp;rsquo;m only seeing enough space for a laptop and hmm not a whole monitor.
Bracket for big screens This one though , wow looks like an extension for your screen too nice.
Hmm permanant tall desk Actually, reading that home Edit site more, I like the concept of just having a tall desk to begin with.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting Vimeo video upload freeze</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-03-28-vimeo-troubleshooting-frozen-uploads/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-03-28-vimeo-troubleshooting-frozen-uploads/</guid><description>2021-03-28 Tried uploading around 2021-03-13
oops.. Asked Vimeo support and answering some questions What version of the app am I running? Version 8.4.1
Any error messages after starting the upload? An error I see when I go to look my videos on https://vimeo.com/manage/videos &amp;ldquo;Optimization pending&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; , &amp;ldquo;This is taking a while. Try refreshing the page, or come back later.&amp;rdquo; when I click on any of the videos there.</description></item><item><title>Trying Databricks</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-03-20-databricks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-03-20-databricks/</guid><description>https://databricks.com/try-databricks
2021-03-21 Running A quick start notebook Based on the notes here, it is pretty easy to create an auto-scaling cluster. Not sure yet what events prompt the cluster to get more workers. But I would be curious to try a job that uses fewer workers and more workers, to see how the outcomes compare. I also like ethat this notebook supports SQL and also python , using what looks like first line as %python to indicate the language.</description></item><item><title>Spark Weekend</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-01-23-spark-weekend/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-01-23-spark-weekend/</guid><description>Trying out Spark this weekend These are just my casual notes from doing that, updating them as I go along.
Following this post to get kubernetes running in Docker for mac Per this post , I just ticked the &amp;ldquo;Enable Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; option in the docker settings. Kubernetes is taking quite a while to start up though . several minutes. kind of weird? Download spark image From here 2021-01-24 ok backup my docker images Per notes , I backed up local docker images, Like this&amp;hellip; docker save citibike-learn:0.</description></item><item><title>Steak Two</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-01-07-steak-two/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-01-07-steak-two/</guid><description>-- Two updates to the earlier steak post. Earlier, I was getting a really low temperature on the meat thermometer I was using and I am pretty sure now that was because I was only dipping just the tip as opposed to basically burying the thermometer lengthwise. This time around I seem to be getting the expected temperature, above 130 F and even above 140 F, whereas before this temperature was not registering even though I had validated that it was working on some pie for instance.</description></item><item><title>notes on Git Internals Git Objects article</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-12-13-article-gitinternalsgitobjects-notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-12-13-article-gitinternalsgitobjects-notes/</guid><description>Reading https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Git-Internals-Git-Objects
(pandars3) $ echo 'test content' | git hash-object -w --stdin d670460b4b4aece5915caf5c68d12f560a9fe3e4 I tried that and oh hah so -w tells git hash-object to actually add that hash to my git key value store database hmm.. lets see if i can find it .. (pandars3) $ file .git/objects/d6/70460b4b4aece5915caf5c68d12f560a9fe3e4 .git/objects/d6/70460b4b4aece5915caf5c68d12f560a9fe3e4: VAX COFF executable not stripped - version 737 Ah indeed. ok binary though. hmm but apparently this is actual data.</description></item><item><title>Easy Blog Posting ("My Noting Book")</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-12-09-dropbox-api-hmm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-12-09-dropbox-api-hmm/</guid><description>For my EasyBlogPosting project.. Testing out the Dropbox API..
2020-12-09 trying this out Per here &amp;hellip; pip install dropbox Went w/ that Getting Started page Through that page, I created a new test app for myself.
Using the API explorer &amp;hellip; I hit Get Token ..
https://www.dropbox.com/oauth2/authorize?response_type=token&amp;amp;client_id=xxxxxxxxx&amp;amp;redirect_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fdropbox.github.io%2Fdropbox-api-v2-explorer%2F&amp;amp;state=file_requests_list!39%2B%2Bxxxxxxxx&amp;amp;token_access_type=online&amp;amp;
That generated a token and I used https://dropbox.github.io/dropbox-api-v2-explorer/#files_list_folder and I was able to see actual folders in my account.</description></item><item><title>Quick test drive this Mozilla/Baidu Deep Speech</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-22-deepspeech/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-22-deepspeech/</guid><description>Summary Ok managed to get DeepSpeech to run, but the output for my voice maybe does not translate to any text that makes sense hahaha. But it was pretty funny to read the interpretation.
My recording was in m4a so I had to change over to wav first ffmpeg is good for m4a to wav conversion but my ffmpeg is having some issues. (deep3) $ ffmpeg dyld: Library not loaded: /usr/local/opt/openssl/lib/libssl.</description></item><item><title>Summary of Mundanity of Excellence</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-14-themundanityofexcellencestratificationandolympicswimmers-summary/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-14-themundanityofexcellencestratificationandolympicswimmers-summary/</guid><description>This is a summary of &amp;ldquo;The Mundanity of Excellence: An Ethnographic Report on Stratification and Olympic Swimmers&amp;rdquo; by Daniel F. Chambliss.
In three sentences The author has spent a lot of time reporting on all levels of swimming competition and writes about observations about the differences between them.
The differences in abilities of different levels of competition are not because of quantitative differences like &amp;ldquo;more training&amp;rdquo; but qualitative differences like using a flip turn instead of just touching the wall and turning around.</description></item><item><title>Rabbit Fever Summary</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-14-newyorker-rabbitfever-rhd-summary/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 11:06:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-14-newyorker-rabbitfever-rhd-summary/</guid><description>The material source &amp;ldquo;Rabbit Rever&amp;rdquo; by Susan Orlean published in &amp;ldquo;New Yorker&amp;rdquo; in the &amp;ldquo;July 6 2020&amp;rdquo; edition
The article in 3 sentences The author writes about how the rabbit, apparently domesticated for hundreds of years now, has been all of livestock, fur source and since mid century a third most popular choice of pet in the US. But a highly contagious and highly lethal &amp;ldquo;Rabbit Hemorrhagic Disease&amp;rdquo; ( RHD the &amp;ldquo;rabbit Ebola&amp;rdquo;) caused by a lagovirus from the Caliciviridae family, has been wiping out populations of rabbits outside the US since 1984, but in mid 2019, dead rabbits fitting the RHD signs were showing up in the islands near Seattle and in Texas, Arizona and New Mexico not long after.</description></item><item><title>Team of Teams Summary</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-12-team-of-teams-summary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 09:30:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-12-team-of-teams-summary/</guid><description>I was reading Team of Teams sometime around September 2019. I at least remember reading it in a really cold Starbucks in a mall in Tokyo haha. First, the standard template:
The book in three sentences Team of Teams is former General Stanley McChrystal&amp;rsquo;s account of his time at the Joint Chiefs of Staff and in his role in the conflict with AQI (Al-Qaeda in Iraq) and Abu Musab al Zarqawi.</description></item><item><title>What I consume</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-02-hmm-what-i-consume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-02-hmm-what-i-consume/</guid><description>Quick idea around more active content consumption My goal is to write about/ annotate what I read/ watch Just came up with a pattern of consumption to enable this. So on a youtube video for example, I can &amp;ldquo;Share&amp;rdquo; into &amp;ldquo;Dropbox&amp;rdquo; , specifically into a new folder say, of just metadata Then I found this youtube api doc where you can actually give the hyoutube api a youtube id and it will give you the metadata, like title, channel name, date, etc Then in a separate place, I can have my actual notes but they can now get linked together more easily, because I have the matching metadata.</description></item><item><title>Notes on multi-multi-class classifiers</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-07-13-multi-multi-class/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-07-13-multi-multi-class/</guid><description>Summary Here is an early draft of a post, trying to extract some of the insights from the project here. There is a lot to write about and I want to just start getting it out.
Quick outline The logloss upper bound Does the &amp;ldquo;k area&amp;rdquo; metric help? training balancing Is it possible to calculate the Bayesian error rate here? And logloss seems to be very sensitive. (can look at correlations , not super high) So what metric should be used ?</description></item><item><title>Some xgboost notes so far</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-06-21-notes-xgboost/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-06-21-notes-xgboost/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s summarize I want to just summarize some learnings from some of my recent notebooks yea.
I have picked up my bike share data learning project from earlier, to try to redo it after having gathered more experience. I want to just jot down some ad hoc thoughts here.
This is mainly around navigating XGBoost.
There are two XGBoost APIs With the sklearn API you can
import xgboost as xgb from xgboost import XGBClassifier import numpy as np from sklearn.</description></item><item><title>Updates</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-05-30-trying-again/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 17:24:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-05-30-trying-again/</guid><description>Summary I tried rebuilding today after 7 months of forgetting how this works and when I tried to jekyll build I got
$ jekyll build Traceback (most recent call last): ... /usr/local/Cellar/ruby/2.6.5/lib/ruby/2.6.0/bundler/lockfile_parser.rb:108:in `warn_for_outdated_bundler_version': You must use Bundler 2 or greater with this lockfile. (Bundler::LockfileError) Per this answer, I ran gem list bundler to see my rubygems version and then gem update --system
$ gem list bundler *** LOCAL GEMS *** bundler (2.</description></item><item><title>Keras Hello WOrld</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2019-05-13-keras-hello-world-fashion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2019-05-13-keras-hello-world-fashion/</guid><description>Here I&amp;rsquo;m doing one of the Keras hello world micro projects, involving classification of tiny 28x28 wardrobe images. This was really fun. ( Here&amp;rsquo;s the original home for the python notebook). One really fun part of this was that at the end I hand drew my own clothing samples, paired them down using the python PIL library and threw them against the classifier. Surprisingly, the mini model performed really well. That&amp;rsquo;s some generalizability!</description></item><item><title>Using ffmpeg to Merge Videos</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2019-03-16-ffmpeg-notes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2019-03-16-ffmpeg-notes/</guid><description>Put together our hyperlapse puzzle videos&amp;hellip; First stab at a merge using ffmpeg time ffmpeg -safe 0 -f concat -i infiles.txt -vcodec copy -acodec copy merged.MOV full output here and used this infiles.txt , following the directions file ./2019-03-09\ 23.03.34.mov file ./2019-03-10\ 01.21.50.mov file ./2019-03-10\ 13.01.46.mov file ./2019-03-10\ 13.03.59.mov file ./2019-03-10\ 13.05.02.mov file ./2019-03-10\ 18.43.53.mov Did it do the right thing? What are my mov lengths.</description></item><item><title>Some plant time lapse</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2018-01-07-plant-hyperlapse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 12:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2018-01-07-plant-hyperlapse/</guid><description>Some time lapse photography.</description></item><item><title>Spoke too soon</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2017-12-01-spokes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 12:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2017-12-01-spokes/</guid><description>Darn, I was riding for at least one to two days thinking, why am I riding much slower? Last night I finally noticed that wow my rear wheel is really wobbly and rubbing up against the breaks quite a bit lately. This morning I finally started setting up to true the wheel. I marked the spoke which looked like adjusting it would have the highest impact. And wow I didnt notice it completely sheared off.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2019-10-19-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2019-10-19-jekyll/</guid><description>First i needed to get ruby from homebrew Using gem install bundler jekyll didn&amp;rsquo;t work for me because I was getting a permission error,
ERROR: While executing gem ... (Gem::FilePermissionError) You don't have write permissions for the /Library/Ruby/Gems/2.3.0 directory. I did brew install ruby and brew install rbenv ruby-build
Also saw this message
(venv3) $ brew install ruby ==&amp;gt; Installing dependencies for ruby: libyaml, openssl@1.1 and readline ==&amp;gt; Installing ruby dependency: libyaml ==&amp;gt; Downloading https://homebrew.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-06-06-heart-datar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-06-06-heart-datar/</guid><description>Does the Wahoo TIKR measure intervals that can be used for Heart Rate Variability measurements? Not sure yet. There are a fitness trackers out there, but I am curious if my chest band can help. I took a quick look at one of my recordings on the Wahoo app, but I don&amp;rsquo;t see anything more granular than just beats per minute. The app indeed has pushed to Apple Health, but I only see the bpm data and no HRV data.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-07-24-understanding-tuning-results/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-07-24-understanding-tuning-results/</guid><description>To explore some of the hyperparameter boundaries with this model, I ran some tests in these notebooks, here and here.
And to get a better understanding of the overfitting-ness / underfitting-ness of models , here , I took the model artifacts and recalculated metrics on the training set, to generate some stats comparing training and testing performance.
Hyperparameter testing (Going to describe this later)
The tuning took several days to complete, but I started plotting early results in this notebook</description></item><item><title/><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-10-20-build-issues-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-10-20-build-issues-again/</guid><description>Build issues again haha I am doing jekyll build but this time from a Makefile , containing
build: jekyll build with make build And I&amp;rsquo;m getting $ make build jekyll build Traceback (most recent call last): 10: from /usr/local/lib/ruby/gems/2.6.0/bin/jekyll:23:in `&amp;lt;main&amp;gt;' 9: from /usr/local/lib/ruby/gems/2.6.0/bin/jekyll:23:in `load' 8: from /usr/local/lib/ruby/gems/2.6.0/gems/jekyll-4.0.0/exe/jekyll:11:in `&amp;lt;top (required)&amp;gt;' 7: from /usr/local/lib/ruby/gems/2.6.0/gems/jekyll-4.0.0/lib/jekyll/plugin_manager.rb:52:in `require_from_bundler' 6: from /usr/local/lib/ruby/gems/2.6.0/gems/bundler-2.0.2/lib/bundler.rb:107:in `setup' 5: from /usr/local/lib/ruby/gems/2.6.0/gems/bundler-2.0.2/lib/bundler/runtime.rb:26:in `setup' 4: from /usr/local/lib/ruby/gems/2.6.0/gems/bundler-2.0.2/lib/bundler/runtime.rb:26:in `map' 3: from /usr/local/lib/ruby/gems/2.6.0/gems/bundler-2.0.2/lib/bundler/spec_set.rb:148:in `each' 2: from /usr/local/lib/ruby/gems/2.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-14-georgia-recount-stats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-14-georgia-recount-stats/</guid><description>Binomial Distribution Plot Binomial distribution for p, and a sample of n
from scipy.stats import binom import numpy as np import matplotlib.pyplot as plt import pylab workdir = &amp;#39;_posts/2020-11-14-georgia-recount-stats_files&amp;#39; fig, ax = plt.subplots(1, 1) n, p = 5, 0.4 mean, var, skew, kurt = binom.stats(n, p, moments=&amp;#39;mvsk&amp;#39;) x = np.arange(binom.ppf(0.01, n, p), binom.ppf(0.99, n, p)) ax.plot(x, binom.pmf(x, n, p), &amp;#39;bo&amp;#39;, ms=8, label=&amp;#39;binom pmf&amp;#39;) ax.vlines(x, 0, binom.pmf(x, n, p), colors=&amp;#39;b&amp;#39;, lw=5, alpha=0.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-14-georgia-recount/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-14-georgia-recount/</guid><description>Here, looking at the recent recount in Georgia as an example around determining, what would a good number of votes to randomly sample to help validate an election result.
According to the latest results of this writing there is
B, T = 2472182, 2458010 p_observed = B*1./(B + T) # 0.501437 For now just starting off below visualizing the binomial distribution around the p_observed for different numbers of samples to look at what likelihoods are assigned to the different outcomes specified by that given binomial distribution.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-03-06-book-summary-the-practice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-03-06-book-summary-the-practice/</guid><description>Reference Title &amp;ldquo;The Practice&amp;rdquo; Author [[Seth Godin]] Book in three Sentences (almost) ( Here&amp;rsquo;s my first stab at this, on [[February 1st, 2021]] ) If you&amp;rsquo;re not on the hook, then you are working as an #amateur or as a #hack Your daily practice is not about doing what you love but loving what you do. Author says if you are not doing for someone other than yourself, then that is also #amateur status.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-03-27-nutrition-calcs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-03-27-nutrition-calcs/</guid><description>Tryingo to figure out whether Calories specified typically include grams from Fiber Managed to find some documentation , here on &amp;ldquo;proximates&amp;rdquo; , &amp;ldquo;Carbohydrate content, referred to as “carbohydrate by difference” in the tables, is expressed as the difference between 100 and the sum of the percentages of water, protein, total lipid (fat), ash, and alcohol (when present). Values for carbohydrate by difference include total dietary fiber content. “Sugars, total NLEA” refers to the sum of the values for individual monosaccharides (galactose, glucose, and fructose) and disaccharides (sucrose, lactose, and maltose), which are those sugars analyzed for nutrition labelling.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-05-23-that-openssl-load-error/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-05-23-that-openssl-load-error/</guid><description>TLDR This time, the brew update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; brew upgrade approach resolved my openssl dyld: Library not loaded woes. And brew apparently no longer has the switch command which had been the cornerstone of a popular stackoverflow answer for this problem.
Trying to run this new ffmpeg usage, but&amp;hellip; $ ffmpeg -i 2021*.jpg -sameq -r 25 outmovie.mp4 dyld: Library not loaded: /usr/local/opt/openssl/lib/libssl.1.0.0.dylib Referenced from: /usr/local/bin/ffmpeg Reason: image not found Abort trap: 6 $ brew update Error: homebrew-core is a shallow clone.</description></item><item><title>blue bottle espresso troubleshooting</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-15-blue-bottle-espresso-troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-15-blue-bottle-espresso-troubleshooting/</guid><description>Trying out this Blue Bottle Opascope espresso w/ this hand grinder w/ my Kamira espresso maker. But the Kamira is not pulling the espresso for some reason.
Comparing the Lavazza grounds to the Opascope grounds I can&amp;rsquo;t tell there&amp;rsquo;s a difference. Is it too fine? Not fine enough?
This is the hand grinder.
Here is what 2 out of 4 of the Blue Bottle pulls ended up like
And after that I did a Lavazza pull and it looked pretty normal.</description></item><item><title>Halloween kitchen sink pipe leak</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-10-31-kitchen-sink-pipe-leak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-10-31-kitchen-sink-pipe-leak/</guid><description>We had a surprise Halloween pipe leak but luckily I got to our local hardware store just 15 minutes before they closed. And they had the pipe I needed. We had guests over that night, so this went much better than the worst case scenario!</description></item><item><title>How to use Github pages with multiple repositories</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-05-31-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-05-31-github-pages/</guid><description>Spoiler alert, don&amp;rsquo;t do it
I wrote some high level and low level markdown summaries for my aviation kaggle data sciency project. I placed them in the github repo of the project itself. Today I have been thinking about how to best build the Github Pages repo to showcase those markdowns that live in that other repository.
Looking for inspiration, I saw this author has chosen to have a typical github.</description></item><item><title>make some xero shoes</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-07-make-some-xero-shoes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-07-make-some-xero-shoes/</guid><description>Made some Xero shoes.</description></item><item><title>Meritocracy Trap Book Summary</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-12-12-meritocracytrap-book-summary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-12-12-meritocracytrap-book-summary/</guid><description>Meritocracy Trap Summary I Read this after hearing an interview with Daniel Markovits initially. (2020-08-23 to 2020-12-12)
The Book in Three Sentences Meritocracy replaced direct inheritance style aristocracy after the post World War II baby boomers overwhelmed colleges&amp;ndash;forcing them to create the SAT to deal with admissions&amp;ndash;and has been snowballing a self reinforcing selection process that has been undoing the middle class ever since. The elite make bank slogging gnarly hours more than by stereotypical capital gains loop holes and &amp;ldquo;the rest&amp;rdquo; work fewer hours, involuntarily left out of the economy.</description></item><item><title>our lock finally bent my key haha</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-01-our-lock-finally-bent-my-key-haha/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-01-our-lock-finally-bent-my-key-haha/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pumpkin Pie Note</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-04-10-pumpkin-pie-cheat-sheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2021-04-10-pumpkin-pie-cheat-sheet/</guid><description>Quick reference for that keto pie Almond flour crust 350 F 2 (1/2) cup almond flour 3 tbspn erithrytol 1/4 tsp sea salt 1/4 cup melted butter Mix dry ingredients with butter first Then add 1 large egg 1/2 tsp vanilla extract Mix again Bake 10-12 min Coconut flour crust 400 F oven 1/2 cup coconut oil (melted) 3/4 cup coconut flour 1/4 tsp sea salt 2 tbspn erithrytol Combine those dry ingredients with oil using a mixer first Then add 2 eggs And mix again Bake around 10 min Filling 325 F oven One 15oz can pumpkin puree 1/2 cup heavy cream or coconut cream 2 large eggs, room temperature 1 (1/2) tsp cinnamon 1/2 tsp ginger 1/4 tsp nutmeg 1/8 tsp cloves 3 tbsp erithrytol 1/4 tsp sea salt 1 tspn vanilla extract Bake for about 50-60 min or until jiggly (jello like) Cool using a fan .</description></item><item><title>Steak Puzzle</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-05-31-steak-puzzle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-05-31-steak-puzzle/</guid><description>I have been trying to solve the steak puzzle for several attempts now. That is, how do you cook a good cast iron to oven transfer? The problem so far has been that the recommended time for the oven for a 450 finish, in this article , 4-5 minutes is the recommendation for a medium steak and 2-4 minutes for a rare.
Although I did not quite follow the 450, I used 400 F, I followed the temperature lore from here last night, using a meat thermometer instead of time, because I suspect oven temperatures in one oven is not the same as that of another.</description></item><item><title>vitamin D</title><link>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-07-vitamin-d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://michal.piekarczyk.xyz/post/2020-11-07-vitamin-d/</guid><description>Vitamin D questions There are a couple mini researach questions I have around Vitamin D. How different are humans with respect to Vitamin D, from other life forms or just other mammals. Also what does the synthesis pathway look like for Vitamin D (or more than one pathway if dietary is a separate pathway from skin). And how exactly does vitamin D enable immune function?
The names. Per 1 , &amp;ldquo;plasma concentration of 25-hydroxyvitamin D&amp;rdquo; is one &amp;ldquo;vitamin D&amp;rdquo; biomarker.</description></item></channel></rss>